surveyscout.com 2018-10-15

# SurveyScout - Discover the Best Free Online Survey Companies

SurveyScout.com takes your privacy seriously, and has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to online privacy. Keep reading to learn more about our information gathering and dissemination practices, and our use of personally identifiable information while on our Web site [www.surveyscout.com](http://www.surveyscout.com/) ("The site", "we", "us").

## IP Addresses

We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our site or web server, and for the general administration of our website. Your IP address, should you decide to register and/or create a SurveyScout account, is also used to help prevent you from creating duplicate accounts.

## Cookies

Upon visiting this web site, a "cookie" is sent to your computer. A cookie is a tiny file that identifies you as a unique user. It stores personal preferences and user data, however, in no way does this tell us who you are. SurveyScout.com has two primary uses for its cookies.

First, we use cookies to track special offers and promotions that may be presented to you as you navigate our website. This is done so that you are not presented with the same special offers and/or promotions over and over, or after you have indicated you are not interested.

Secondly, we use cookies as part of our authenticaton system when you login to your account. If you select the "remember me" option when logging in, our site will set a cookie so that you do not have to login again the next time you visit SurveyScout.com.

While both of these activities depend on the use of a "cookie," visitors to this site always have the option of disabling cookies in their web browser. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent.

The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

## Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ or our third party tracking utility partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. 

## Information Gathering

This Privacy Policy applies to end-users that access the Site, and/or register for the products and/or services offered by and through the Site. The types of personally identifiable information that we collect at the Site, during registration and when you participate in surveys or contest may include, without limitation, any of the following: your full name, street address, e-mail address, password, date of birth, ethnicity, and gender. In addition, we may request information about your use of, or interest in, the types of products and services offered by the third party sellers with whom we have partnered to offer you the products and services available at the Site.

From time to time we may ask you for personal health information about you or someone you may provide care for. The types of information we may ask for is whether or not you suffer from a certain medical condition. We use this information to match you up with research studies that apply to you. We do not share this information with anyone. 

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the opt-out/modify section below.

## Information Dissemination and Use

All information SurveyScout collects, as described above, is used to tailor our content and help our advertisers and partners understand the demographic breakdown of SurveyScout's members. These practices are essential to keep SurveyScout's membership free. All personally identifiable information submitted to SurveyScout remains your property, however, all information you submit to SurveyScout grants SurveyScout the right to use that information as set forth herein. Without limitation, Survey Scout may use your personal information, within and subject to state and federal law, for legal purposes, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request to: (a) bring selected market research, retail, and other opportunities and promotional offers to you via direct mail marketing, e-mail marketing, telemarketing and/or online banner advertising; (b) when responding to offers and opportunities provided by SurveyScout or when necessary and; (d) for validation, suppression, content improvement and feedback purposes. SurveyScout uses the information you provide to provide you free information and personalized content about products and services that may be of interest to you. Additionally, we use contact information collected from our Site to send you information about the company, to keep you informed of products and services that may be of interest to you, and to notify you of changes to this policy or changes/improvements to the site itself, provide you with rewards, allow you to view your rewards balance, redeem your rewards for merchandise and/or cash, and to allow you to participate in surveys provided by us or third parties. In addition, you agree that we may contact you with updates and/or any other information that we may deem appropriate for you to receive in connection with your account and/or the Site. We also use this information to personalize your experience with SurveyScout and to contact you regarding any Focus Groups that may be in your area. Contact information is also used to reach you, when necessary, regarding the use of our Site, products and/or services. None of the personal information collected will be sold or distributed to third party companies except on an aggregate basis to help our advertisers and partners understand the demographic breakdown of SurveyScout's members or if required by law.

We may provide your personally identifiable information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as sending out emails on our behalf or offering customer support. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

We do not sell your personally identifiable information to third parties.

## Social Media (Features) and Widgets 

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Links to Other Sites

SurveyScout.com expects its partners, advertisers and affiliates to respect the privacy of our users. Be aware, however, that third parties, including our partners, advertisers, affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. For example, during your visit to our site you may link to, or view as part of a frame of content that is actually created or hosted by a third party.

Also, via our site you may be introduced to, or be able to access, information, websites, features, contests or sweepstakes offered by other parties. SurveyScout.com is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

## Children Under 13

SurveyScout.com does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from or about children under 13 except as permitted by law. If we discover we have received any information from a child under 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe SurveyScout.com has any information from or about anyone under 13, please contact us at scoutsupport@surveyscout.com .

## Security

This web site has security measures in place to protect against loss, misuse and/or alteration of the information that you provide. Furthermore, we have taken every precaution technically possible to prevent any unauthorized access to the contents of this web server. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

When you enter sensitive information (such as personal health information) on our forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

## Opt-Out/Modify

SurveyScout.com provides every user with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving future communications from us, change, delete inaccuracies, and modify personal information previously provided, or remove their information from our databases altogether. You may contact us to do so in any of the following ways:

  1. Email: scoutsupport@surveyscout.com
  2. Website: [Contact us here](http://surveyscout.helpserve.com/)
  3. Postal Mail: 1675 Larimer Street, Suite 640, Denver, CO 80202 USA
  4. Phone: 813-749-7149
  5. You may also login to your account at any time to change, delete inaccuracies, or modify your personal information. 
  6. You may also unsubscribe from receiving communications from us by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each communication. 
  7. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

If you're a SurveyScout member and you simply wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, you are encouraged to visit our Account Cancellation page or email us at scoutsupport@surveyscout.com. Upon entering your User ID and Password your account - and all information we have on file for you - will be instantly and permanently deleted from SurveyScout.

## Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Contacting SurveyScout.com

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this web site, or your dealings with this web site, please contact us via one of the methods above.

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

This Privacy Policy was last updated June 29, 2016.
